tutors without a doubt are some of the
best cards to have in your commander
deck for the uninformed a tutor in Magic
the Gathering is not someone who teaches
you how to play it is a spell or an
ability that searches up a card in your
deck and most of the time either puts it
in your hand or on top of your library
currently the three best tutors of all
time are demonic Tudor vampiric Tudor
and Imperial seal but today I'll be
going over a Tudor that is often
forgotten and overlooked plus it can be
put in practically every single
commander deck and the best part is it
only costs a dollar
let's check out Moon silver key
so for Just Two Mana we get an artifact
that says pay one tap sacrifice Moon
silver key search your library for an
artifact with a minor ability or a basic
land reveal it put it into your hand and
Shuffle
so this card's absolute flaw is that it
can search for a basic land but the
thing most players skip over and forget
is about this part
artifact with a mana ability
so let's make sure we're all on the same
page
what is a minor ability well at its core
a minor ability is an activated or
triggered ability that could create mana
and it doesn't use the stack basic lands
birds of paradise and Arcane Cigna are
all examples of cards with activated
minor abilities
whereas cards such as overgrowth or
Gauntlet of power all have triggered
minor abilities
now that we've got that out of the way
the first card that comes to everybody's
mind when you say artifact with a minor
ability is definitely soldering but what
about these cards you might not know you
can search up plus two extra spicy cards
that make moon silver key even better
first up there's the artifact lands
they're artifacts and they also produce
Mana
in a similar vein you also have the mer
minor Bros minor producing artifact
creatures
another favorite artifact creature with
a minor ability of mine is goldhound if
you have them Moon silver key is a
fantastic Tudor for these key combo
enablers such as astronauts alter
feraxian Alta Clan Ironworks and
doubling Cube
if you're playing an Aristocrats deck
Moon silver key is just an alter tutor
which is exactly what the deck wants to
find as soon as possible
there are a bunch of nice utility
artifacts that also Grant you Mana that
you can fetch up with moon silver key
too
the celesters and the great henge are
great for drawing extra cards glistening
sphere is a fetchable proliferate or you
could just go with staff of completion
pyromancer goggles can double up spells
and you even have a fetchable Angel's
Grace With The Golden Throne
machine Squad Effigy and Cursed Mirror
are just clones and strix Haven Stadium
even has an inbuilt win condition
and in a pinch you can even search up
permanent removal with unstable Obelisk
and let's not forget about the other
sort of cards we can search up for
artifacts with triggered Mana abilities
so cards like extra planar lens cage Sun
forsaken Monument Gauntlet of Might
Gauntlet of power these are all
searchable Mana doublers and some of
them even come with a bonus static
ability now there are plenty of other
cards that I've not listed here that you
can search up with moon silver key
but if that isn't enough options for you
then how about looking towards
biotransference and encroaching
microsynth biotransference is a four
minor enchantment that makes all of your
creatures artifacts including creature
spells you control and creature cards
you own that aren't on the battlefield
in addition whenever you cast an
artifact spell you lose one life and
create a 2-2 black necron Warrior
artifact creature token
encroaching microsynth is a four minor
artifact that says non-land permanence
you control are artifacts in addition to
their other types the same is true for
permanent spells you control and
non-land permanent cards you own that
aren't on the battlefield
so biotransference makes all of your
creatures artifacts including the wands
in your deck
and similarly encroaching microsynth
changes all of your permanent spells and
non-land cards in your library into
artifacts too so now Moon silver key can
search up many more excellent cards
the few main ones that come to mind are
kinen bonder Prodigy which can double up
your minor producers grinning ingness a
combo starter for Red Storm decks and
the soon to be released delighted
halfling to ensure your creature spells
can't get counted of course there are
many many more options to choose from
now am I saying Moon silver key is the
best tutor in Magic absolutely not
is it a very good one most definitely
I hope this video has convinced you not
to forget about Moon silver key the next
time you're building a deck
what's your favorite card that players
seem to have forgotten let me know in
the comments down below and I'll see you
guys next time